# 酒香浓郁
Rich in wine flavour,
# 花哨的东西没有 但是就是原汁原味
nothing flamboyant, just the real deal
# 做的太好吃了
sooo freaking good.
# 看这个 肥而不腻入口即化
Just look at this, melting in mouth,
# 东坡肉 这是传统菜 大名菜啊
Dongpo pork, a famous, traditional dish.
# 你这个烧法是传统烧法
You are showing the traditional cooking technique today, eh.
# 五花三层 这肉还是不错啊
Three layers of fat here, nice pick!
# 薄厚合适 先燎一下毛
It's the right thickness. Start by torching its hair.
# 这个燎一下非常好
Very important step here this is,
# 一个是把毛燎了 另外还去腥
For one it removes all the hair, it also removes the gaminess
# 火燎可以 把锅烧热了蹭一蹭也可以
Do it with direct flame (or blow torch), or just rub the skin on a smoking hot pan
# 火燎会更好
But it's better to just torch it
# 火苗的外边温度
Cuz the out rim of the flame is slightly hotter than the pan
# 要比锅里温度稍微高一些
Cuz the flame is slightly hotter than the pan
# 直接可以把毛的根部
Could burn off the root of the hair, easily
# 燎的非常的干净
# 所以要烧到这种糊的状态
Remember to torch it, until, burnt
# 糊了之后一会一洗
Wash it afterward
# 会变成那种黄颜色
The pork will change to yellow
# 而且烧完黄之后 然后一刮
Plus, after torching it, you scrap the skin
# 还便于吸收汤汁当中的颜色
it helps the skin to absorb the sauce
# 出来的肉皮的也好看
the end product will look much nicer.
# 好了 表面起泡泡了
Voilà, bubbling on top.
# 东坡肉在杭州四川全都有
This dish is common in Sichuan and Hangzhou,
# 这些都是过去苏东坡
where Su Dongpo served as a gov. official
# 在那边为官过
# 而且苏东坡也喜欢美食
and he loved his food
# 所以他擅长的也要做一些菜
also enjoyed making them.
# 享有盛名的在四川是东坡肘子
The Sichuan variant features pork hock,
# 在杭州是东坡肉
while the Hangzhou's use belly.
# 好了 搁这里 温水泡上
Now soak it in warm water.
# 先刷刚才烧的第一块
Brush off the burnt bits.
# 好了干净了 这表面颜色又红
Look, done, it's pink-ish on the skin.
# 颜色很漂亮
The color looks great!
# 出水吧 出水了
Let's drive some of its remaining blood out.
# 常温的水大约三十来度
Use warm water around 30 Celsius (86F), boil it to remove the blood
# 煮肉出水 要让肉当中的一些血水
# 还有异味都要慢慢地渗出来
... and some of the smelly tastes
# 高的温度下去之后
If you start with hot water, the meat will contract
# 它就会迅速收缩 表面收缩之后
# 把所有的味道血水
locking up all the blood, so that they remain in the meat
# 它全部会挤到里面 它就吐不出来了
# 所以要近似于这种常温的水
So, start with warm water.
# 表面它不凝固就行了
Just make sure there's no oil coagulate on the surface
# 也不一定非得是零度的水
Don't need to use freezing cold water.
# 加上点黄酒 这得煮一会呢
Pour in some cooking wine, and boil it for about an hour
# 煮一个来小时
# 葱 姜 开锅给煮透了煮透了它
Green onion, ginger, boil it thoroughly
# 第一刚放进去之后煮时间不长
At beginning, we are not boiling for too long
# 那么用筷子你扎的时候是扎不动的
so you won't be able to poke it with chopsticks
# 扎不动的肯定是不熟
meaning it's not cooked.
# 那么还有一种情况下
After a while, white liquid will emerge after poking it,
# 扎完之后它会冒白水
# 这就证明熟是刚熟 但是没熟透
This means the meat's almost cooked, but not quite
# 一定是扎进之后拔出来
The meat is fully cooked when nothing leaks out (after poking), right?
# 没有多余的水冒出来的时候
# 就是证明煮透了 是吧二伯
The meat is fully cooked when nothing leaks out (after poking), right?
# 歇会
Ou, take a rest
# 大爷您看这孩子多好啊
See Da Ye, a good lad here,
# 大约我们这两块煮了一个小时
We boiled it for an hour, that's enough.
# 差不多了 时间不短了对吧
# 这一扎就透
You see how easy it goes through!
# 一定要煮到筷子一插能透进去
You have to boil till the pork is easy to poke through.
# 这是一个很关键的点
It's important that you reach this stage!
# 煮熟是一个步骤
The purpose of parboiling, is to keep its shape in later cooking
# 是为了让它成型是比较好看
# 蘸一下水
dip in water
# 煮的过程当中 它的肌肉会收缩了
The muscle will contract in the boiling process, so that it won't curl again later
# 那么你再加热 它就不容易变形了
# 所以就出来形状比较好看
This way the end product will look a lot nicer.
# 大小块跟家里边的您个人习惯来定
Cut to the size of your liking,
# 边要去一下
trim off the sides,
# 好 差不多了 它不会再抽了
That 'bout it!
# 这型有时候还得借着这个肉
The shape follows the meat,
# 下边还是一样 下边不整齐
trim the bottom too, it's not very square there.
# 对 讲究不将就
no compromises here
# 正好改四块
Perfect fours.
# 搁这里行了 一会回锅肉了
Trimmings go here, could make some Twice cook pork later(we have a video for this one)
# 葱姜 放一个大料瓣 一个大料
Green onion, ginger and one star anise.
# 有这个大料 但是它不影响肉的香味
This star anise won't take away the meatiness
# 也不压过盖过其它的
and won't out shine our other seasonings.
# 咱们的调料的味道
# 只是加了一个复合味
It adds some depth to the flavour.
# 锅里放油 开始煸小料了
Oil in,
# 先煸大料瓣 姜葱
First, in with star anise, green onion and ginger,
# 慢慢煸 到煸出黄色
until it takes on some color
# 这是什么 黄酒
What's this? Huangjiu cooking wine
# 倒黄酒
Cooking wine, in
# 冰糖倒进去
Rock candy, in (can replace with caster/fine sugar)
# 生抽
Light soy sauce, in
# 淮扬菜东坡肉它酒香味比较浓一点
Huaiyang version of this dish is richer in wine flavour
# 所以黄酒量稍微大一点
so you might use a bit more wine here
# 突出的是酒香味
to feature the aroma of cooking wine.
# 把肉放进去
Add in the meat
# 先炖皮的地方 上色
Give some colour to the skin, (skin on the bottom)
# 但是一定要注意 锅底特别薄的
Pay attention if you are using sticky pots (like stainless)
# 火一大特别容易粘
The meat will stick and burn if you turn the heat too high,
# 下面可以垫一个竹箅子隔一下
you can get away with some spacers on the bottom.
# 这个水位水量不够 还得加点热水
The water is not enough, add more
# 要漫过肉来
until the meat is submerged
# 加点老抽调下色
Adds some color using dark soy sauce,
# 酒香浓郁 甜咸适中
Rich and flavourful!
# 要是不用高压锅 要个要炖多久
How long, if not using the pressure cooker?
# 一百分钟 一个半小时
100 minutes, roughly one and a half hours
# 一定要大火烧
Boil it with high heat
# 烧完之后 肉皮当中的胶原蛋白
That way, the collagen will absorb the colour
# 会把颜色吸进去 然后就关小火
Once the meat picks up good colour, turn the heat to low
# 慢慢的焖一小时 焖
braise for one hour
# 这就是我们在菜谱当中写到的
That's why you see in many cook books
# 大火烧开十分钟
Place the heat to high, boil for 10 mins
# 然后以小火炖制一小时
And braise for an hour, or an hour and a half
# 或者一个半小时
# 还有一些师傅
Some also tie the meat with twine, to keep its shape
# 用马兰草给它捆一下
# 这就是防止这个肉散掉
to keep its shape
# 如果要是选五花的中部这一块
The mid portion of the belly is ideal,
# 还是非常好的 因为它肥瘦相间
there's a nice balance between lean and fat
# 如果是靠下边比如软那层五花
If you use the fattier part, it will fall apart
# 夹起来以后它会很散掉
it is easy to fall apart
# 但是硬的五块肉这地方
While if you use this tougher part (closer to loin),
# 它熟了之后它是紧致的
It is firmer when cooked.
# 所以是不一样的
See the difference? So you want to pick the tougher cut when choosing your belly.
# 选肉的时候是要用硬五花
So you want to pick the tougher cut when choosing your belly.
# 得了关小火咱们炖上一百分钟
OK, lets simmer for 100 mins.
# 用高压锅 炖出来一样
It's the same result if using the pressure cooker,
# 待会一收汁 没问题
No problem what's so ever, if we properly reduce the sauce
# 二伯照着
Er Bai, keep an eye on it.
# 高压锅压多久呢
How long in the pressure cooker though?
# 四十分钟正合适
45 minutes will do.
# 肉好了 筷子轻轻一捅就进去了
See the meat is ready, the chopstick goes through just like  that
# 不费劲
Effortless.
# 行了别捅了 一会全是扎的眼儿了
Enough poking, pal. Holes are all over the place
# 把肉捞到一个地方
Take the meat out
# 篦一下 把渣子篦出去
Strain the liquid
# 汤里边的葱姜都要捡出去
Get rid of the ginger, green onion
# 这会皮就不能朝下 一定要朝上了
Now, Remember to keep the skin side up.
# 翻过来 开始收汁了
And start to reduce the sauce
# 大火收汁 收到剩一半
On high heat, reduce half of the liquid
# 现在这个原料 它的猪皮比较薄
Cuz the skin is kinda thin, not enough collagen's cooked out
# 含胶原蛋白比较少
# 所以汤汁的粘稠度还是达不到
the sauce is not as sticky
# 所以一会儿我们收汁的时候
So when we reduce the sauce,
# 还要适当勾点芡
we need to use a bit of slurry!
# 这味道不错 味道好极了
That's good taste!
# 咱们做东坡肉的过程当中
In the braising process
# 因为经过加热挥发
due to the heating and evaporation,
# 咱们里边酒香味已经不够了
the aroma of cooking wine is not enough.
# 所以我们要补上一部分 再滚一下
So we add some to compensate, then boil for another while
# 把肉先起出来
Take out the meat, plate it
# 装好盘了 勾点芡啊 增加粘稠度
Some slurry in, thick up the sauce
# 边倒边搅 别着急
Stir while pouring, don't rush
# 慢慢让它糊化
Let it thicken.
# 锅下边看它慢慢起了小泡泡
You see it's bubbling at the bottom,
# 证明它已经开始慢慢糊化 温度够了
meaning it's thickening up
# 一次倒多了就够呛 就成咕嘟了
It'd be a disaster if you pour it all in.
# 没问题
Voilà,
# 来一点明油
a bit of scallion oil
# 关火
Off the heat.
# 红亮
Look at the red shine meat!
# 东坡肉
This IS Dongpo pork
# 下力一压 散了都
Even falls apart like this
# 火候正合适 恰到好处
Right on point.
# 看这个 空心馒头
Here, with some "flat" Mantou (aka Chinese steamed buns)
# 吃起来肥而不腻入口即化
It's light in texture and melts in mouth.
# 二伯
Er Bai. come on
# 大爷爱吃肥的 肥的入口即化
Da Ye like it fat, it melts
# 大爷后边的牙齿有点毛病
Da Ye cannot chew lean meat with his back teeth.
# 这牙吃瘦吃不了 只能吃肥的
can only chew the fat part.
# 好几天没吃这么香的肉了
It's been a while since last eaten meat this good.
# 到这才叫大爷呢
Way to go Da Ye!
# 其实这个肉
Actually, it'd be more flavourful, if we don't use the pressure cooker
# 要在原锅里边炖一个半小时的话
and just stew it for 90 minutes
# 这肉就更香
The meat will be more fragrant.
# 但是我们为了节省时间
But we used pressure cooker, to save some time
# 放到高压锅里头
# 应该说效果也不错
the result's not bad!
# 二伯 再不尝就凉了
Er Bai, taste it now bro.
# 接着锅尝
just use the pot as your bowl
# 带着空心馒头
have it with flat Mantou
# 我就不一一说了
I am not going to details
# 说点关键的
directly summarize it
# 调味的六大要素
Six aspects of seasoning
# 隋坡掌握的是完全面面俱到
Sui Po mastered well in every aspect
# 调料的运用他相当到位相当准确
The precision of seasoning is phenomenon
# 你看淡淡的酒香味 肉的酥烂
You see, the wine flavour, the tenderness
# 他一切的调料都是
Everything he did is to enhance the meatiness
# 为了增加肉的香气味
# 你看有的人就吃料味 他不是
Many people overpower with spices, but not him
# 就一个大料就烧出满满的香气味
One simple use of star anise brought out so much flavour
# 他最关键的是什么
The key here, he's got the right balance between sweet and savoury.
# 他甜咸味掌握的太准了
# 南方人太甜 我真不喜欢吃
Personally, I don't like the over-sweet Southern cuisine,
# 但是今天他这东西我太能接受了
But I liked his dish today,
# 我还能吃一块
Can have one more piece.
# 但是今天不好意思了
A bit guilty if I do though!
# 批准 二伯再吃一块
Approved! Have another one, Er Bai!
# 所以说隋坡对被烹饪的理解
Sui Po's understanding of cooking
# 和他掌握的这种技巧
and his skillset, is very rare among the young generation
# 我跟你说 在年轻人当中
# 实属难能可贵
and his skillset, is very rare among the young generation
# 花哨东西没有
Nothing flamboyant, but all down to the basic
# 但是就是原汁原味
# 做的太好吃了
So good.
# 隋坡把师父这点精髓全掌握了
Sui Po mastered everything a master can teach.
# 您说这话我怎么那么爱听啊
Heh, I like that compliment!
# 谢谢二伯
Thanks Er Bai,
# 我再来一块 得特批一块
I'll have another piece, special approved piece.
# 我得好长时间没吃肉了
It's been awhile!
# 你们谁爱吃谁吃
Eat as you like, it's sooo good
# 太香了